Important information

I am currently a master's student here with a research focus. However, I am more **interested in practical jobs and industries than in theoretical studies**. In fact, I have **4+ years of experience** in software engineering and development. Therefore, I am currently looking for a full-time position in Germany.

If I am hired and work full-time, I am willing to skip my master's course. Under current German rules, there is no problem with hiring, since I have a German-recognized (Anabin H +) 4 years Bachelor Computer Science, and Engineering University degree. Therefore, I just require a full-time permanent job contract to start working for the company. I don't require any visa sponsorship or re-location assistanc.



Md Sajedul Haque Romy

Profile

Seasoned, forward-looking
Software Engineer with a
background of 4+ years in creating
and implementing innovative
software solutions to enhance
business success. Committed to
maintaining effective
communication and intend to learn
from the team.

Contact

Address

Rothenburger Str. 145, 90439 Nuremberg, Germany

Phone

+4915733929916

Email

romi0199@gmail.com

Portfolio Website

https://demo.codebangla.com **Github**

https://github.com/codebangla LinkedIn

https://linkedin.com/in/mrromi/

Education

(April 2020 - Present) MSc in Medical Engineering (Medical Image and Data Processing)

Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg, Germany

(January 2011 - May 2017) BSc in Computer Science and Engineering

University of Information Technology and Sciences, Bangladesh

Experiences

(June 2021 - Present) <u>Up2u Gmbh</u> (Werkstudent, part-time)

- → Planning user story, design mockup with **Miro**
- → Developing platform with Ionic Angular, NodeJS and web backend with C#, ASP.NET Core 6, SQL server, MongoDB NoSQL, Angular 13, Docker and Azure Cloud
- → Creating features for WordPress, Woocommerce
- → Implementing Inbound marketing with SEO, SMM.

 lay 2017 March 2020) Togumogu.com (Software Engire

(May 2017 - March 2020) <u>Togumogu.com</u> (Software Engineer, full-time)

- → Provided **consultation** for domain and server installation and **tech stack viability**
- → Developed front-end, JWT Authentication, Authorization with **Angular 6** from **WEB RESTful APIs**
- → Setup Debian Linux Server with SSH and DNS and Email
- → Deployed the ecommerce application on Nginx (May 2010 - April 2017) CodeBANGLA (Self Employment,

(May 2010 - April 2017) CodeBANGLA (Self Employment, part-time)

- → Created Prescription management system for Doctors with C#, Winform, .NET 4.0, SQL Server
- → Created ERP for Power supply company with React JS, C#, NodeJS, ASP.NET Core, Entity Framework, SQL Server
- → Created Order Management System with VueJS, Node JS, Laravel, MySQL, Redis NoSQL and Ionic JavaScript Framework for Android

Languages

English (IELTS 7.0, C1)

Deutsch (A2)

Bangla (Native language)

Accomplishments

Sales growth increased 19% from previous year and improved online Branding at up2u

Transformed the ideation phase into an ecommerce platform for online sales at Togumogu

Achievements

April 2017

Local Lead

NASA Space App Challenge

December 2014

Mentor

National Hackathon Bangladesh

May 2013

Microsoft Techelite Asia

September 2010

Top 10

Alo Ashbei Mobile Apps ContestBy

Microsoft & Grameenphone

References

Christian Gruber

Head of Business Development & Sales

Up2u Gmbh

christian.gruber@my-up2u.de

(January 2009 - April 2010) <u>Scriptlance.com</u> (Freelance Developer, full-time)

→ WordPress, PHP Pro Bid, SMF forum software and other CMS softwares

Skills

Backend

→ C#, ASP.NET Core 5.0+, REST API, Backend Validation, JWTToken, Authentication, Authorization, ORM, Laravel 8.0+, GraphQL, NodeJS

Frontend

→ TypeScript, ES6+, Angular 11+, RxJS, NgRx, React, Redux, Clientside validation, Bootstrap 5.0, Material, Winform, WPF, XAML, Windows Store Apps, Ionic Angular, Route Guard, Accessibility, WebBrowser Storage, Authentication

Databases

→ SQL Server, MySQL, SQLite, Redis, Postgres, MongoDB, NoSQL

Testing

→ Backend Unit Test, JEST, CyPress

Dev Tools

→ Visual Studio 2019, VS Code, Postman, Insomnia, Git, Chrome Devtools, PuTTY, Bitvise, FileZilla, PowerShell

Project Management Tools

→ MS Teams, JIRA, Asana, Slack, Hipchat

Deployment

→ Azure, Windows Server, IIS, Debian, Ubuntu, Apache, Nginx, OpenShift, Digital Ocean, Docker, k8s

Architectures

→ MVC, MVP, MVVM, Repository Pattern, UoW Pattern, SOLID, Onion Architecture, Clean Architecture, Microservices, Areas, UML, SOA, BDD

Others

→ Communication within cross-functional teams (Business and Tech), Digital Marketing, AIS (financial accounting), ERP, Blockchain, DLT, Power BI, Financial Innovation, Requirement Engineering, MS Project, Gantt Chart, Scrum environment